Implementierung des JS-Teils
============================

In this section, you are going to code the Application using JavaScript.

Creating and linking the scripts
---------------------------------

Die benötighten Javascript-Dateien werden mit Hilfe des ``script``-Tags am Ende des HTML-Files eingefügt. Dies sorgt dafür, dass eventuell vom Javascript benötigte Klassen und IDs bereits im HTMl-Dokument vorhanden sind, wenn das javascript geladen wird.


.. code-block:: HTMl

                ....
                </footer>
            </div>
            <script src="questions.js"></script>
            <script src="script.js"></script>
        </body>
    </html>



Creating the question bank in the form of objects
---------------------------------------------------

Die jeweiligen Fragen und Antworten müssen in irgendeiner Weise dem Programm zur Verfügung gestellt werden. In unserem Falle stehen diese Informationen in der Datei questions.js. Sie werden in json-Notation definiert. In einer späteren Version werden wir diese Daten remote beziehen, um ein Cheaten zu vermeiden.

.. code-block:: javascript

    var questions = [
        {
            "question": "Web pages are designed using?",
            "option1" : "HTML",
            "option2": "CSS",
            "option3": "Javascript",
            "option4": "Jquery",
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Web pages are designed using?",
            "option1" : "HTML",
            "option2": "CSS",
            "option3": "Javascript",
            "option4": "Jquery",
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "____ makes websites dynamic",
            "option1" : "CSS",
            "option2": "HTML",
            "option3": "Javascript",
            "option4": "Bootstrap",
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What is HTML used for?",
            "option1" : "Skeleton of website",
            "option2": "Design a website",
            "option3": "Make website dynamic",
            "option4": "Database of a website",
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Which CSS property changes background color?",
            "option1": "colour",
            "option2": "bgColor",
            "option3": "color",
            "option4": "background-color",
            "answer": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "Which selector selects all the elements in CSS?",
            "option1": "*",
            "option2": "+",
            "option3": "$",
            "option4": "#",
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of a in a+=b where a=10 & b=5?",
            "option1": "10",
            "option2": "5",
            "option3": "15",
            "option4": "20",
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What does 'document' denote in a javascript statement?",
            "option1": "Javascript file",
            "option2": "Css file",
            "option3": "HTML page",
            "option4": "XML document",
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which function is used to calculate an expression?",
            "option1": "calculate()",
            "option2": "calc()",
            "option3": "evaluate()",
            "option4": "eval()",
            "answer": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you call a function? ",
            "option1": "call.function_name",
            "option2": "function_name.call",
            "option3": "call(function_name)",
            "option4": "function_name()",
            "answer": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "Javascript statements should end with a ... ",
            "option1": "Comma",
            "option2": "Semicolon",
            "option3": "Period",
            "option4": "Exclamation",
            "answer": 2
        }
        ];


Step by step algorithm for the JavaScript code of the app
---------------------------------------------------------

Create and initialize the variables
-----------------------------------


Retrieve the necessary HTML elements to manipulate them later
-------------------------------------------------------------


Initialize more variables
---------------------------------------------------

Function that sets the random question and options in the app
-------------------------------------------------------------

Function that updates the progress bar with each question
---------------------------------------------------------


Function that changes the option buttons to their default color
---------------------------------------------------------------


Get question function - consolidates and calls the mini functions
-----------------------------------------------------------------

Functions to change tracker colors, calculate final score & set result page
---------------------------------------------------------------------------


Generate a unique random number to call a random question/answer set
--------------------------------------------------------------------

Generate a unique random number to call a random question/answer set - part 2
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

Make the timer work - part 1
----------------------------

Make the timer work - part 2
----------------------------

Make the timer work - part 3
------------------------------

Make the option selection work
------------------------------

Make the next question button work - check and load next question
-----------------------------------------------------------------

Consolidate everything and make the app work on refresh
-------------------------------------------------------

Check the output and correct bugs
---------------------------------

